Guide to the Marcus Cunliffe papers, 1960-1990 MS0125.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Research notes and articles, 1823-1988; MS0125 Series 6; 14 Linear feet (Box 46, Box 45, Box 66, Box 65, Box 64, Box 63, Box 69, Box 68, Box 67, Box 58, Box 70, Box 71, Box 72, Box 62, Box 61, Box 60, Box 59, Box 57, Box 55, Box 56, Box 74, Box 73, Box 75, Box 49, Box 50, Box 47, Box 48, Box 53, B
  - Thomas Paine -- reputation, 1859-1984 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Thomas Wolfe, 1950 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Time magazine (Warren Commission report), 10/02/1964 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Twain, Thackeray, Barnum - 19th century Anglo-American literary and popular culture, 1908-1986 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Twentieth century manifestations -- individualism (4th and 5th weeks), 1957-1959 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - U.S military - original court martial papers, notes, and bibliography, 1836-1955 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - United States in comparative perspective - notes, 1955-1970 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Upton Sinclair, undated (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Various newspaper and magazine clippings, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - W.H. Prescott on Cortes and Montezuma and Cunliffe's notes, undated (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Wage slavery, 1977 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - War of 1812 bibliography, 1952 (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Washington, DC - articles about, 1830-1982 (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - Washington, DC - contemporary news clippings, 1977-1988 (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - Watersheds in American attitudes about the past, 1955-1962 (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - Wealth and property - articles, 1966-1981 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - William Faulkner, 1951-1954 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - William James - notes, 1901-1988 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - William James - notes, 1901-1988 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - William James - notes, 1944-1985 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - William James and psychology, 1977-1981 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - William James and psychology, 1977-1981 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Winfield Scott (soldiers and politics), 1970 ca. (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Women and the Constitution, 1988 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Women, Property, and Law - articles, 1980-1986 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson on George Washington, 1968 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Writings on American and American influences, 1939-1967 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Writings on American Culture and History, 1959-1970 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Writings on democracy, 1957-1978 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Wyoming -- individualism, 1961 (Box 75, Folder 6)
- University teaching career, 1965-1990; MS0125 Series 7; 6.5 Linear feet (Box 79, Box 78, Box 76, Box 77, Box 83, Box 82, Box 81, Box 75, Box 80, Box 85, Box 84)
  This series consists of materials related to Cunliffe's career as a university professor in England and the U.S. This includes course outlines and syllabi, lecture notes, exam questions, and student papers.
  - English Universities: American Intellectual History - course outlines, 1973-1982 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    General note
  - English Universities: American Intellectual History - course topics of study, 1965-1983 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - English Universities: Aspects of American Thought - course syllabus, notes, 1974-1983 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - English Universities: American Intellectual History - Report on the Teaching of American Intellectual History, 1960 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - English Universities: American Intellectual History to 1865 - notes for class History 571, 1973-1981 (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - English Universities: American Intellectual History 1800-1900 - notes for class Fall term, 1974-1975 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - English Universities: Aspects of American Identity - notes for class, Fall and Spring term, 1965-1973 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - English Universities: Comparative Aspects of American Thought - notes for class History 867.1, 1969-1970 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - English Universities: Comparative Approaches to American History - notes for class HIST 684 (Fall 1973), 1966-1973 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - English Universities: Course - American City, 1970-1976 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - English Universities: Course -- American History, 1763-1861, 1976 ca. (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - English Universities: Course -- Authority and Consent in the U.S., 1776-1800, 1970-1977 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - English Universities: Course - City and Country in America, 1967-1975 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - English Universities: Course -- Contemporary History, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - English Universities: Course -- History of American history (historiography), 1964-1970 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - English Universities: Course -- Individual in History, 1967-1973 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - English Universities: Course -- National and World History, 1975 ca. (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - English Universities: Course -- Progressive Impulse in the U.S., 1900-1917, 1966-1977 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - English Universities: Course -- Realism and Reform in American History and literature, 1872-1918, 1969-1977 (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - English Universities: Course -- The Gilded Age in American Literature and Society, 1865-1900, 1967 (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - English Universities: Marcus Cunliffe bibliography, 1949-1989 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - English Universities: Cunliffe's lecture notes - American Foreign Policy, undated (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - English Universities: Cunliffe's lecture notes - American Foreign Policy, undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - English Universities: Cunliffe's lecture notes - American history outline, undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - English Universities: Cunliffe's lecture notes - American Literature, 1829-1914, undated (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - English Universities: Cunliffe's lecture notes - Britain through American Eyes, undated (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - English Universities: History of American Presidential Assassination - notes for class, 1976 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - English Universities: Individual in History - notes for class, 1967-1974 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - English Universities: Modern American Presidency - notes for class (Fall 1968), 1963-1987 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - English Universities: Private Property: The History of an Idea in America - notes for class Hist 201 (Fall 1981), 1977-1981 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - English Universities: Seminar readings - "The Supreme Court as a Moulder [sic] of American Society" (case examples), 1965 ca. (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - English Universities: Syllabi for classes, 1965 ca. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - English Universities: University of Sussex -- "Founding to Foundering,", 1964-1982 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University: American civilization intro course - AMCV 71, Fall, 1988 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - George Washington University: American Intellectual History - general, 1982 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - George Washington University: American Intellectual History - notes for class HIST/AMCV 771, 1983 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - George Washington University: American Intellectual History since 1945 - notes for class AMCV 772 (Spring 1983), 1956-1983 (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - George Washington University: American Intellectual History: Idea of Private Property - notes for class AMCV 771, Fall, 1984 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - George Washington University: American Intellectual History: Idea of Private Property - notes for class AMCV 771, undated (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - George Washington University: American Intellectual History: The Idea of Private Property - notes for class, 1987-1988 (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - George Washington University: American Intellectual History: The Idea of Private Property - notes for class, 1987-1988 (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - George Washington University: American Intellectual History: The James Family - exam questions for class HIST/AMCV 772, 1986-1989 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University: American Intellectual History: The James Family - notes for class HIST/AMCV 772, including graded final exam, 1985-1989 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University: American Social and Intellectual History to 1861 - notes for class, undated (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - George Washington University: American studies department at GW - syllabi and memos, 1985-1989 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University: American Studies International newsletter (published by GW), 1988 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University: Annual reports of GW faculty members -- Cunliffe, 1980-1989 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University: "Augustus John Foster and the 'Washington Wilderness'" by Marilyn Parr (GW thesis), 1987 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University: Class and comprehensive exams, 1982-1985 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - George Washington University: Class materials for class on Henry James family, 1905-1988 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University: Class syllabi, reading lists for Cunliffe's classes, 1982-1987 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University: Class syllabi, reading lists for Cunliffe's classes, 1983-1985 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - George Washington University: Comparative Approaches to American History and Culture - notes for Hist/AMCV 773 course (Spring 1990), 1970-1990 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University: Comparative Approaches to American History - course notes, 1984 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University: Comparative Approaches to American History and Culture - handouts of readings for class AMCV 773, Spring, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University: Comparative Approaches to American History and Culture - notes for class AMCV 773 (Spring 1990), 1979-1990 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University: Comparative Approaches to American History and Culture - notes for class AMCV/HIST 773 (Spring 1990), 1975-1990 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - George Washington University: Comparative Approaches to American History and Culture - notes for class AMCV/HIST 773 (Spring 1990), 1975-1990 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - George Washington University: Correspondence and memos - Library and Bookstore, 1981-1986 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University: Course - American Intellectual History, 1980 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University: Cunliffe's annual reports as faculty member, 1980-1985 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - George Washington University: Cunliffe's commencement address to Arkansas College (see also Oversize Material, Box 98), 05/21/1988 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University: Cunliffe's convocation address to GW students, "George Washington: The Man and His University", 02/1982 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University: Cunliffe's courses taught - syllabi, notes, and exams, 1984-1985 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University: Cunliffe's speech for GW Honors Convocation, 03/23/1990 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University: Cunliffe's submissions for "GW Report" newsletter, 1981-1988 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - George Washington University: Dissertation: "Coming Home from the 'Good War'" by James Deutsch - chapter 1 with comments from Cunliffe, 1991 (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - George Washington University: Dissertation: "Coming Home from the 'Good War'" by James Deutsch - chapter 2, undated (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - George Washington University: Dissertation: "Coming Home from the 'Good War'" by James Deutsch - chapter 3, undated (Box 81, Folder 11)
  - George Washington University: Dissertation: "Coming Home from the 'Good War'" by James Deutsch - chapter 4, undated (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - George Washington University: Dissertation: "Coming Home from the 'Good War'" by James Deutsch - chapter 5, undated (Box 81, Folder 13)
  - George Washington University: Dissertation: "Coming Home from the 'Good War'" by James Deutsch - chapter 6, undated (Box 81, Folder 14)
  - George Washington University: Dissertation: "Coming Home from the 'Good War'" by James Deutsch - Appendix 1: Bibliography of Novels Depicting World War II Veterans, undated (Box 81, Folder 15)
  - George Washington University: Dissertation: "Coming Home from the 'Good War'" by James Deutsch - Appendix 2: Filmography of Motion Pictures Depicting World War II Veterans, undated (Box 81, Folder 16)
  - George Washington University: Dissertation: "Coming Home from the 'Good War'" by James Deutsch - Appendix 3: Bibliography of Secondary Sources - post WWII U.S. history, undated (Box 81, Folder 17)
  - George Washington University: Doctoral student Barbara Shuttleworth -- papers, exam questions, 1984 (Box 81, Folder 18)
  - George Washington University: Doctoral student Carol Stapp -- papers, 1981-1982 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University: Doctoral student Carolyn Sung -- final exam notice, notes, 1984 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University: Doctoral student David Kirkham -- papers, reading lists, memos, 1984-1988 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - George Washington University: Doctoral student Dorothy Pennino -- papers, reading list, exam questions, 1987-1988 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University: Doctoral student Frank Millikan -- papers, reading lists, memos, 1983-1984 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University: Doctoral student Krystyna Puc -- reading lists, exam questions, 1984 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University: Doctoral student Leopoldo Nuti -- correspondence, memos, 1981-1984 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University: Doctoral student Peggy Brown -- correspondence, memos, transcript, 1985 (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - George Washington University: Doctoral student Yu-Lan Guo -- correspondence, memos, 1988 (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - George Washington University: Draft of Robert Scott's dissertation - "St. George Tucker,", 1990 (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - George Washington University: Draft of Robert Scott's dissertation - "St. George Tucker,", 1990 (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - George Washington University: Draft of Robert Scott's dissertation - "St. George Tucker,", 1990 (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - George Washington University: Evaluation by Cunliffe of a colleague's manuscript "Rhetoric of War,", 1987-1988 (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - George Washington University: Exam questions and notes for course on American Intellectual History to 1861, AMCV/HIST 771, 1981-1984 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University: Exam questions and class notes for course on the Henry James Family, AMCV/HIST 772, 1980-1988 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University: Feature on Cunliffe in GW Times, Fall, 1990 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - George Washington University: "GW Report" newsletter, 1981-1988 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University: "GW in the News" newsletter, 1983-1985 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University: GW scholarly journals, 1989 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University: Handbook for Sponsored Research Programs at GW, 1987 (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University: History Department meetings, American Studies self-study and assessment, 1987-1988 (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - George Washington University: History of Heroism - notes for class AMCV 774, Fall, 1984 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - George Washington University: History of Heroism - notes for class HIST/AMCV 774 (Fall 1985), 1950-1985 (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - George Washington University: History of Heroism - notes for class HIST/AMCV 774 (Fall 1985), 1952-1985 (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - George Washington University: Idea of Private Property - syllabus and notes for class HIST/AMCV 771, 1987-1988 (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - George Washington University: Invitations from schools for visiting professorships - outside USA, 1983-1984 (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - George Washington University: Memos papers, minutes, course syllabi of the GW American Studies Department, 1980-1987 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University: Miscellaneous papers, 1987 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University: Monarchy, Republicanism, and the Americas - course notes, 1981 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - George Washington University: Monarchy, Republicanism, and The Americas - notes for class UNIV 102 (Spring 1981), 1966-1982 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University: Nan Ernst - research assistant, 1985-1987 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University: Notes for AMCIV 771 class -- American Intellectual History, 1981-1982 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University: Notes for Cunliffe's Commencement address at George Washington University, 1981 (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University: Notes on American Studies International, 06/1990 (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - George Washington University: Notes, memos, and drafts of Robert Scott's dissertation - "St. George Tucker,", 1990 (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - George Washington University: Phi Beta Kappa at GW - 50th anniversary, 1988 (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - George Washington University: Republicanism in America - notes for class AMCV 773, Fall, 1982 (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - George Washington University: Republicanism in America - notes for class HIST 772 (Spring 1984), 1886-1984 (Box 84, Folder 12)
  - George Washington University: Republicanism in America - notes for class AMCV/HIST (Spring 1984), 1983-1984 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University: Republicanism in America - notes for Hist/AMCV 773 course (Fall 1987), 1877-1987 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University: Republicanism in America - notes for Hist/AMCV 773 course (Fall 1987), 1889-1987 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - George Washington University: Student papers by Jennifer Keene ("Athletics in WWI Training Camps" and "Theodore Roosevelt"), 1985-1986 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University: The Great Popular Author in Britain and America, 1800-1915 - notes for AMCV/ENG 775 course (Spring 1986), 1867-1986 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University: Visit of Asa Briggs to GW, 01/29/1988 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University: Woodrow Wilson Center- correspondence and papers, 1981 (Box 85, Folder 7)
- Pamphlets papers, and reprints, 1950-1988; MS0125 Series 8; 5.5 Linear feet (Box 91, Box 92, Box 86, Box 93, Box 85, Box 96, Box 90, Box 89, Box 94, Box 88, Box 95, Box 87)
  This series consists of reprints and pamphlets on a variety of subjects, and features such authors as Charles Sumner, Charles Francis Adams, Arthur Schlesinger, Bernard Bailyn, Cushing Strout, Carl Degler, Oscar Handlin, C. Vann Woodward, Walter Lippman, and MacKinlay Kantor. The series also includes the Lincoln Lore Bulletin from 1966-1990. NOTE: Not all of the pamphlet titles are noted in the folder lists.
  - Papers and Reprints: American Public Policy - writings by Richard Rose, 1988 (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Papers and Reprints: "Amerkanische Spiegelungen Shakespeares Melville, Whitman, Eliot" (in German) by Hans Galinsky, 1965 (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Papers and Reprints: Article reprints sent to Cunliffe (one by Bernard Bailyn), 1962-1967 (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Papers and Reprints: Article reprints sent to Cunliffe, 1956-1969 (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Papers and Reprints: Article reprints sent to Cunliffe, 1965-1968 (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - Papers and Reprints: Articles by John Shelton Reed, 1983-1987 (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - Papers and Reprints: Articles on Emerson and Lincoln, etc. by Barry Schwartz, 1985-1988 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Papers and Reprints: Articles on the British Military by Brian Holden Reid, 1986 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Papers and Reprints: Booklet - "The First Portrait of Washington,", 1892 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Papers and Reprints: C. Wright Mills, 1946-1954 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Papers and Reprints: "The Development of Frederick Jackson Turner as a Historical Thinker" - excerpt from Colonial Society of Massachusetts journal, 1939 (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Papers and Reprints: "Lincoln Lore" bulletin, 1966-1970 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Papers and Reprints: "Lincoln Lore" bulletin, 1971-1974 (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Papers and Reprints: "Lincoln Lore" bulletin, 1975-1978 (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Papers and Reprints: "Lincoln Lore" bulletin, 1979-1982 (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - Papers and Reprints: "Lincoln Lore" bulletin, 1983-1986 (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Papers and Reprints: "Lincoln Lore" bulletin, 1987-1990 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Papers and Reprints: "A Metaphor for the History of American Criticism" by Marshall van Deusen, 1961 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Papers and Reprints: The Nation, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Papers and Reprints: "Optimism" by Margaret A. Boden, from Philosophy: The Journal of the Royal Institute of Philosoph, 10/1966 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Papers and Reprints: Pamphlets on religion, 1952-1967 (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Papers and Reprints: Paper - "Alden Partridge" by Allan Nash, 1956 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Papers and Reprints: Paper - "Comparing the Incomparable: Politics and Ideas in the United States and the Soviet Union" by Robert Kelley, 1983 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Papers and Reprints: Paper - "James Bryce and America during the Progressive Period -- Some New Evidence" by Richard Crockett, 1981 (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Papers and Reprints: Paper - "James Wilson's New Meaning for Sovereignty" by Garry Willis, 1987 (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Papers and Reprints: Paper - "Lawrence Stone and Women of Late-Seventeenth Century England: Evolution and Critique" by Lois Schwoerer, 1981 (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Papers and Reprints: Paper - "Republicanism and Historical Consciousness in 19th Century America" by Dorothy Ross, 1983 (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - Papers and Reprints: Paper - "The Attitude of the colonists toward the King and Royal Power during the Decade of Controversy" by June E. Uphaus, 1960 (Box 87, Folder 12)
  - Papers and Reprints: Paper - "The Human Figure in the Tragedies of Shakespeare" by J. Leeds Barroll, undated (Box 87, Folder 13)
  - Papers and Reprints: Paper - "The 'New' Regionalism" by Clarence Mondale, 1982 (Box 87, Folder 14)
  - Papers and Reprints: Paper - "The Rediscovery of America" by Alan K. Henrikson, 1981 (Box 87, Folder 15)
  - Papers and Reprints: Paper "Dickens goes West" by Lawson/Peoples, undated (Box 87, Folder 16)
  - Papers and Reprints: "A Pretty Story" by Peter Grievons, 1774 (Box 87, Folder 17)
  - Papers and Reprints: "Popular Government by Divine Right" sermon by Dr. Bushnell, undated (Box 87, Folder 18)
  - Papers and Reprints: "Practical and Visionary Americans" by Quentin Anderson, 1976 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Papers and Reprints: "The Press and the American Revolution" edited by Bernard Bailyn, 1980 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Papers and Reprints: "Radical Religion and the American Political Novel" by Cushing Strout, 1976 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Papers and Reprints: "The Shaping of America" by Page Smith, 1981 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets: A - Adams, Charles Francis The Sifted Grain and the Grain Sifters (1900); Allen, H.C. American History in Britain (1955); American Influences Abroad (1950); Asselineau, Roger "`Mourning Becomes Electra' as a Tragedy", 1958, undated (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets: A - Allmand, C.T., Henry V (1968);1876 - American Art of the Centennial (1976); The American Character (1962); A Message from Roosevelt from Beyond the Border (1992); American Studies/Regional Studies, 1980, undated (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets: A - American Literary Realism, 1870-1910 (journal) (1967); Ames, Russell Social Realism in Charles W. Chestnut (c.1952); America and the Mind of Europe, Mid-Century (Saturday Review of Literature 01/1951), undated (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets: A - American Painting, 1815-1865 (exhibit catalogue, n.d.); American War (Civil War pamphlet, c.1865); American History and the Massachusetts Historical Society (n.d.), undated (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Pamphlets: B - Bicentennial Notes on George Washington (1931); Butterfield, Herbert The History of Science and the Study of History (1959); Buxton, Christopher A British Assessment of the American Economy, undated (Box 88, Folder 9)